over the last three weeks I have spent
day and night researching testing and
eating Oreo ice cream to make the best
version on the internet there are eight
critical steps in this recipe where if
something is done wrong you will end up
with a very different ice cream in terms
of both taste and texture the goal ice
cream that tastes like real cookies and
cream while having the macros to eat
this every day to top it off I will show
you one trick to level up your Oreo ice
cream that I haven't seen anyone else
use before
let's get into it grab a high sided
container get it on a scale and add one
Oreo which is the first crucial step in
making a proper cookies and cream ice
cream you may be wondering why add an
Oreo now and not just add one in as a
mix in later well since we will be
adding protein powder shortly we want to
take the edge off the protein powder
flavor we will inevitably produce I
tried using up to four Oreos in this
step and found that one gives us the
most bang for our buck while still
allowing us wiggle room for additional
goodies later oh my God test seven
tastes better than test eight even
though it has one less Oreo I'm baffled
over the Oreo pour 410 grams fat-free
high protein milk and 4.2 grams vanilla
extract almond milk will make this ice
cream more icy and will have less of an
ice cream mouth feel while significantly
reducing protein so I don't advise using
it unless you don't drink milk for
whatever reason if you have calories to
spare you can use two percent or even
whole milk to get the top tier cookies
and cream experience grab a measuring
cup and add one scoop whey protein
preferably one that is cookies and cream
if you follow the channel you know I
usually use a whey casing blend in my
recipes but from multiple taste tests I
found that casein part of the protein
powder makes this recipe into an
extremely thick gelato-like consistency
this is so weird they spun up almost
like like cottage cheese
yeah I'm gonna go cookies and cream
if you prefer a gelato like consistency
then feel free to blow your load on away
casein cookies and cream flavor instead
even more important than the type of
protein is the overall flavor of the
protein itself I would rather have a
good cookies and cream protein over
vanilla but that is not what I'm
referring to Here I Am specifically
talking about the quality of the flavor
itself this one definitely looks more
like ice cream the way only
neither of them give me that cookies and
cream vibe that I'm looking for which is
sad
if you use a vanilla protein that tastes
like ass I can assure you that your ice
cream will taste like ass not the good
kind either I will link the protein
powders I recommend in the pin comment
that guarantee high quality and good
flavor profile and you can use code E4
or CM for an additional 10 off we will
follow that up with 10 grams erythritol
and 4 grams black cocoa powder black
cocoa powder is exactly what Oreo uses
in their cookies and is why they are so
dark so it would be skimpy of me to use
anything else finish that off with a
half gram of salt and a half gram of
xanthan gum mix those dry ingredients
together thoroughly grab an immersion
blender and start mixing the wet
ingredients slowly start adding the dry
ingredients by allowing a small amount
of it to drop in then waiting until it
dissolves before adding in a little bit
more do this over a 30 second period and
then continue mixing the melted ice
cream for an additional 90 seconds add
the finished ice cream to a pint put a
lid on it and add it to your pantry of
creamies we will then take this bag and
place it in the freezer details to come
later the detail I also put into my
cookbook is second to none from calorie
charts to Kitchen Essentials to detailed
pictures of every one of my 120 plus
recipes this cookbook has it all plus it
keeps updating when I make new recipes
and you get to make them before anyone
else start eating new recipes before
they get uploaded to YouTube by clicking
the link in the pin comment and using
code e4cm for 10 off time to start a 24
hour countdown on your phone because
this is so damn good you don't want to
wait even one minute longer after it's
ready 24 hours later grab your pint
rinse it under hot water for one minute
and mix it on the sorbet setting the
sorbet setting may sound weird but each
ice cream recipe is individual and needs
an individual setting that it should be
mixed on for the most ice cream like
consistency after going through all of
the functions for this recipe I landed
on the sorbet function being the best
while the light ice cream setting was a
close second this is what they look like
after being spun back to back the
greatest feat that needs to be conquered
for every creamy recipe that has mix-ins
is to make sure they break down the way
you want them to unfortunately with
creamy's current mix and setting almost
all mix-ins break down into crumbs I
needed to find a way to change that I
tried putting the Oreos directly into
the center as ninja advises that just
ended up with tiny particles of Oreo
through my ice cream I then tried
freezing the Oreos and putting them in
the middle after the first spin the
final result was beautiful chunks but
the Oreo was a weird Frozen consistency
that wasn't very good I needed to come
up with an alternative and I wondered if
putting the Oreos off center would make
a difference this was my first major
breakthrough because I got big chunks of
Oreo and many bites however they weren't
the correct texture I then needed a way
to get chunks of Oreo that have a soft
cookie mouth feel like that in a real
tub of Frozen ice cream one night after
dinner I was enjoying some more Oreos
and milk for the perfect night cap I ate
a few of them and as they melted in my
mouth I had a come to Jesus moment what
if I dunked the Oreo in milk until it
starts to get soft then freeze it my
theory was since the cookie was already
soft before freezing that by the time it
goes into the ice cream and gets mixed
it will stay chunky from being frozen
but melt enough to be soft like in real
Oreo ice cream and sweet mother of
Christ on the 25th attempt it worked
this will be a our final ice cream
God yes I'm so excited
this one tastes more like Oreo
[Music]
I knew it this is the darker one this is
one of the black cocoa powder we got the
final recipe in the book and it only
took
three weeks
after putting the pint in the freezer
get about four ounces of milk in a glass
dunk an Oreo for 15 to 20 seconds and
place it in a plastic bag repeat for the
next Oreo if you plan to make this ice
cream on the reg which you will I
suggest doing six to eight Oreos at a
time close up the bag and throw it in
the freezer with your creamy pints once
the sorbet spin finishes take a knife
and make a hole near the edge of the
Pint grab the Oreos from the freezer and
cut them in half fill that hole up with
Oreos cover the Oreos with the ice cream
you took out load it back up and hit
that mixing setting FYI the Oreos come
back up to room temperature very quickly
it is important you don't take the Oreos
out until it is time to add the mix-ins
while the Oreos get mixed in chop up one
more Oreo for a topping this will give
us a perfect contrast of crunchy Oreos
on the top with soft chunks throughout
the cream let's pull the cream out top
it with our Oreo pieces grab a spoon and
enjoy the best Oreo protein ice cream on
the internet if you want to level up
this ice cream even further simply grab
a waffle cone add a couple scoops and
enjoy the fruits of your labor
[Music]
damn you've been looking good from the
back girl
Oreos and ice cream have always had a
spot in my heart but so has cereal
luckily if you have extra pints you
don't have to choose one or another in
this video here I use three of the most
popular cereals in the world and make a
custom ice cream base to go with each
one of them to create a low calorie
treat that is great any day of the week
when hunger strikes choose the flavor
you have a taste for until next time
deuces